square2marketing.com 2019-07-11

# Privacy Policy

_Last Updated: May 25, 2018_

Your privacy is very important to us, and Square 2 Marketing ("S2M", "we", "us" or "our") is committed to conducting our business in accordance with privacy principles in order to ensure that the confidentiality of personal information is protected and maintained. This Privacy Policy applies to the S2M Websites (www.square2marketing.com and any other web-based platforms; collectively, the "Websites") and governs our data collection, processing and usage. Access to and use of the Websites, and the services provided on the Websites (collectively, the "Service"), will be subject to this Privacy Policy as set forth below.

This Privacy Policy covers the following topics, and links to the specific sections:

Information We Collect

How We Use The Information

Cookies And Other Tracking Technologies

How We Share And Disclose Information To Third Parties

Security Of Your Personal Information

Your Privacy Rights

International Data Transfers

California Residents

Links To Third-Party Websites

Children

Changes To This Privacy Policy

Contact Us

* * *

## **Information We Collect**

We gather various types of information, including information that identifies you as an individual ("Personal Information") from our users, as explained in more detail below.

We may collect Personal Information directly from visitors to our Websites that you choose to send to us or provide to us; for example, on our "Schedule My 30-Minute Marketing Assessment" (or similar) online form, if you register for a S2M webinar or if you choose to download a whitepaper or any similar resource. If you contact us through the Websites, we will keep a record of our correspondence.

In addition, we may use "cookies" and other tracking mechanisms to collect information from the users directly from the browsers, including your device's IP address, referring website, what pages your device visited, and the time that your device visited our Website (further described below).

* * *

## **How We Use The Information**

We will use the information we collect via our Websites:

  * To administer our Website, our events and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, statistical and survey purposes;
  * To improve our Website to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * To analyze customers' use of the Websites for trend monitoring, marketing and advertising purposes;
  * For purposes made clear to you at the time you submit your information – for example, to fulfill your request for a consultation, to provide you with access to one of our webinars or whitepapers or to provide you with information you have requested about our Services; and
  * As part of our efforts to keep our Website safe and secure.

We may also use the information you send to us via the Websites and/or Services, to communicate with you via email and, possibly, other means, regarding products, services, offers, promotions and events we think may be of interest to you or to send you general marketing information, if this is in accordance with your marketing preferences. However, you will always be able to opt-out of such communications at any time (see the "Your Choices" section below).

* * *

## **Cookies And Other Tracking Technologies**

Our Websites may use "cookies" and other tracking mechanisms to collect information about you when you visit our Websites. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of and our affiliated websites, we ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.

**About cookies.** A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

**Cookies that we use.** As explained in more detail below, S2M and third-party advertisers may send one or more cookies to your browser to help customize your experience on our Websites or Services or to provide you with ads that may be of interest to you.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * Authentication and Personalization - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our Websites and as you navigate our Websites and Services, and to store information about your preferences and to personalize our Websites and Services for you.
  * Security - we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our Websites and Services generally.
  * Advertising - we use cookies to help us to display content that will be relevant to you.
  * Analysis - we use cookies to help us to analyze the use and performance of our Websites and Services.

The S2M and third-party cookies you may encounter on our Websites include, but are not limited to:

  * www.square2marketing.com (website navigation, security, analysis)
  * www.google.com (use tracking and content interests)
  * www.doubleclick.net (use tracking and content interests)
  * www.hs-analytics.net; www.hs-scripts.net; www.hscta.net; www.hsforms.net (marketing tracking to provide a better user experience)
  * www.hubspot.com; www.hubspot.net (marketing tracking to provide a better marketing experience)
  * www.luckyorange.net (user website interaction to provide a better user experience)
  * www.usemessages.com (website chat feature)
  * www.facebook.com (personalization)
  * www.twitter.com (personalization)

You may review the cookies in use by third-party service providers at any time by viewing site information from your browser. This is typically displayed to the left of the address bar of your browser.

**Managing cookies.** Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

S2M expressly requests that you consent to cookies when you visit its Website.

**Strictly Necessary Cookies:**

S2M's Websites use cookies that are strictly necessary to the provision of the Services. These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you on the Website. Currently, S2M's Websites do not include any necessary cookies. As such, you can decline all cookies and still use the Websites and Services.

**Permissive Cookies:**

These cookies are not necessary to the functioning of the website and a visitor to the Websites must opt-in to the use of these cookies.

  * www.square2marketing.com
  * www.google.com
  * www.doubleclick.net
  * www.hs-analytics.net; www.hs-scripts.net; www.hscta.net; www.hsforms.net
  * www.hubspot.com; www.hubspot.net
  * www.luckyorange.net
  * www.usemessages.com
  * www.facebook.com
  * www.twitter.com

**"Do Not Track"**

Some browsers have incorporated "Do Not Track" mechanisms. Most of these mechanisms, when turned on, send a signal to the website or online service indicating that the user does not wish to be tracked online. For more information about Do Not Track mechanisms, see <http://allaboutdnt.com/>. S2M does not monitor or respond to Do Not Track browser requests.

* * *

## **How We Share And Disclose Information To Third Parties**

We do not rent or sell your Personal Information to anyone. We may share and disclose information (including Personal Information) about our customers in the following limited circumstances:

**Third Parties:**

We may share your information with third-party vendors, consultants and other service providers ("Service Providers") that we employ to perform tasks on our behalf. These companies include (for example) our payment processing providers, website analytics companies (e.g., [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), described below), product feedback or help desk software providers, CRM service providers (e.g., HubSpot), email service providers and others.

We utilize Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google, to better understand your use of our Websites and Services. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit the Websites, what pages they visit and what other sites they used prior to visiting. Google uses the data collected to track and examine the use of the Websites, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the data collected on the Websites to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Google's ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Websites is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Google offers an opt-out mechanism for the web available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

We also use HubSpot, a web-based marketing platform, to provide customer relationship management services for our sales and marketing. HubSpot collects personal information via S2M's Website on S2M's behalf, including your name and email address. HubSpot processes the data collected only to allow S2M access to and use of that information. HubSpot does not share that information with any other entity. HubSpot's Privacy Policy is available [here](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy).

We do not share any Personal Information with these Service Providers without your express consent.

**Business Transfers:**

We may choose to buy or sell assets, and we may share and/or transfer customer information in connection with the evaluation of and entry into such transactions. Also, if we are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy or go through some other change of control, Personal Information could be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party. Any such sale, transfer or otherwise sharing of our assets shall be subject to the restrictions of this Privacy Policy and any applicable data protection laws.

**Additional Disclosures:**

We reserve the right disclose personal information about you with your permission, as required by law, as necessary to enforce our any agreements we may have with you or Privacy Policy, to investigate or defend against third-party claims or allegations, to protect the security and integrity of our Services and property, to protect our rights or personal safety and that of our users or others and to respond to valid requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

* * *

## **Security Of Your Personal Information**

We take into account the state of the art, the costs of implementation and the nature, scope, context and purposes of processing as well as the risk of varying likelihood and severity for the rights and freedoms of natural persons, and implement appropriate technical, physical and organizational measures to ensure an appropriate level of security to protect the personal information that we collect and process, both while in transit and while in storage. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we use reasonable security safeguards to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee absolute security.

* * *

## **Your Privacy Rights**

You can always opt not to disclose information to S2M. However, some information may be needed to use our Services.

**Cookies**

You can accept or reject cookies through our website. You can also do so by adjusting your web browser controls.

**Marketing Communications**

At any time, you can withdraw your consent and opt out of receiving promotional or marketing communications from S2M by using the unsubscribe link in the emails communications or by visiting [the request page](https://www.square2marketing.com/resources/individual-rights-request).

If you have any account for our Services, S2M will still send you non-promotional communications, like service-related emails.

**Exercising Your Data Subject Rights**

You have the right to access, review, update, rectify and delete any Personal Information that S2M holds about you, or exercise any other data subject rights available to you under applicable data protection laws. In order to exercise your data subject rights, you can submit a request via [info@square2marketing.com](mailto:info@square2marketing.com). S2M's Privacy Team will review any request and respond within a reasonable time.

Please note that we may still use any aggregated and de-identified Personal Information that does not identify any individual. S2M will also retain any Personal Information to the extent necessary to comply with S2M's legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce S2M's agreements, as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

* * *

## **International Data Transfers**

Personal Information you submit on the Websites or through the Services is sent to the United States and will be primarily processed by us in the United States. If you choose to use our Websites or Services from regions outside the United States that have laws governing data collection and use that differ from U.S. law, you acknowledge and agree that you are transferring personal information outside of that region to the United States and, by providing such information, you consent to the use of your personal data as identified in this Privacy Policy and the transfer of your personal data to the United States.

* * *

## **California Residents**

California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of Personal Information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to: [info@square2marketing.com](mailto:info@square2marketing.com).

* * *

## **Links To Third-Party Websites**

For your convenience, hyperlinks may be posted on the Websites that link to other third-party websites. We are not responsible for, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to, the privacy practices of any third-party linked sites or of any companies that we do not own or control.

* * *

## **Children**

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 16. If you are under 16, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any Personal Information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us Personal Information, please contact us at [info@square2marketing.com](mailto:info@square2marketing.com).

* * *

## **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change or modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will alert you to material changes by, for example, placing a notice on our Websites and/or by sending you an email (if you have registered your email details with us) when we are required to do so by applicable law. You can see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the date at the top of this page. You are responsible for periodically reviewing this Privacy Policy.

* * *

## **Contact Us**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policies, please contact us at [info@square2marketing.com](mailto:info@square2marketing.com), and our Privacy team will respond within a reasonable time.
